Kyle Knutson

Consultant



Summary

Over seven years of analyst and testing experience working in complex systems as a Software Quality Assurance Analyst, Business Systems Analyst, Implementation Associate, Test Lead, Subject Matter Expert, and Trainer. Highly motivated, analytical individual who is team oriented. Flexible, self-manageable, able to process and apply new skills and concepts quickly. Excellent written and verbal communication skills that help facilitate collaboration between Project Managers, Testers, Developers and Business partners to coordinate complex solutions to meet business line needs.

Education

- Bachelor of Arts Urban Studies : Spatial Analysis and Planning (minors in Geography and Sociolgy), University of Minnesota Duluth, 2007
- Master of Arts Urban Planning, Minnesota State University Mankato, 2009

Skills	
Software Quality Assurance	Requirement Analysis and Test Planning
Business Process and Technology Implementation	 Application Training and Performance Support
Waterfall SLDC	Agile Methodology (Scrum and Kanban)
Front and Back Office Testing	Defect / Issue Management
Requirements Gathering and Validation	Big Data Testing
User Acceptance Testing	Test Lead

Professional Experience	
Sogeti Cargill – Team Phoenix	June 2019 - Present

Sr Consultant

- Big Data testing for Finance, Analytics, Insights, and Reporting (FAIR) views created for Corporate Finance analytics and insight platform
- Drive testing for views and tables created by Data Engineers using SQL scripts in Hadoop and verifying data from SSAS using Power BI
- Validate data ingestions from Oracle SQL to the Hadoop Corporate Finance Data Lake
- Create and manage test cases in ALM Octane while using the Kanban delivery method. User stories tested in Dev, QAS and Prod environments

Kyle Knutson Page 1

• Track issues and updates via communication with Business Analysts, Product Owners and Data Engineers within individual User Stories and Teams during initial testing throughout deployment.

Sogeti	March 2019 – June 2019
Cargill - Scales Team	Maich 2019 – Julie 2019

Sr Consultant

- Execute functional and regression testing for software upgrades for manual use and compatibility
 with existing scale programs and printers. Tested for two new scale programs and one existing scale
 that is soon to be discontinued
- Provide a foundation for the Scales team for internal and external Scale software and programs
 used by Argo and Farming sites across the country by creating a Test Plan, Test Scripts and
 Regression scripts that can be used for current and future projects
- Partner with multiple 3_{rd} party developers and product owners in order to execute test cases, problem solve, report defects, resolve defects for scale software updates on a tight timeline
- Ensure accurate Gross, Tare, and Net weights are captured and reported within the guidelines and settings of Avery Weigh-Tronix and Mettler Toledo scale software updates

Accenture Mortgage Cadence	December 2017 - March 2019
----------------------------	----------------------------

Test Engineering Senior Analyst

- Serve in Support Role to manage and resolve Breakfix, Hotfix, Reapplies, and Payload tickets during test cycle for a SaaS based Mortgage Software
- In Project Role, responsible for test planning, test execution, issue resolution during Functional Test, Smoke Test, Integration Test and Regression Testing phases in Agile environment
- Work with team of Product Owners, BA's and Devs using daily scrum meetings to communicate project status while using TFS and MTM to track progress on sprint /project backlogs
- Use Microsoft SQL to confirm backend database system communication with SaaS to verify complex financial calculations and documents
- Run code migrations, hotfix appliers, run SQL scripts, and manage web system path changes when ticket fixes and environments are packaged and ready to be moved for QA and Dev
- API testing in Postman and GraphQL environments

Accenture	May 2017 - December 2017
Best Buy	Play 2017 December 2017

Test Engineering Senior Analyst

- Analyze and Review Business and Functional requirements to create Test Plan and create test suites to help transition from Legacy applications to Accenture ideated solutions
- Test in Oracle DB using SQL queries to condition and verify test data for sign systems at Best Buy, Systems include a web based and mobile applications used to create and audit paper and digital sign displays used in all North American Best Buy locations
- Execute test cases, open defects and track test status progress using Team Foundation Server for release and regression scenarios
- Create and manage daily report of 1000's of test cases and list of open defects to Project Managers and Development team for onshore and offshore teams, to clearly report project status and potential areas of need

Wells Fargo Consumer Test Management	February 2016 – May 2017
--------------------------------------	--------------------------

Systems Quality Assurance Analyst

Kyle Knutson Page 2

- User acceptance tester for Direct Auto and Personal Lines and Loans for Sales, Underwriting Fulfillment and Booking departments based upon a quarterly release schedule
- Develop, review and analyze business requirements and design documents for business process updates to loan application originations, fulfillment and closing document packages
- Partner with Project Mangers, Technology Managers and Implementation teams to ensure smooth transition of technology updates for our customers and employees impacted
- Assists in the creation, preparation, and implementation of systems quality assurance reviews and the development and execution of test plans and test scripts in HP ALM
- Identify risk and report defects for UAT and Production issues in ClearQuest and PAC 2000

Wells Fargo	June 2013 – February 2016
Consumer Financial Services	

Implementation Associate

- Subject Matter Expert testing software for conversion to new credit application platform producing over \$100 Million in monthly loan volume
- Develop and maintain Process and Procedures documents along with process flows to assist in training over 300 team members adapt to new policy and technology changes
- Collaborate with project managers and business partners to develop business requirements
- Manage new projects and implement system updates from test to production environment
- Create and execute test scripts track project test status and metrics
- Identify, report and monitor defects for UAT and Production issues to resolution

Wells Fargo	June 2011 – June 2013
Consumer Financial Services	Julie 2011 – Julie 2013

Inbound Sales Specialist

- Achieved 108% of unit goals by averaging 45 new loans and \$600,000 in volume per month
- Originate and review credit applications for quality and eligibility for auto credit products
- Engage customers to analyze and identify needs and potential financial opportunities
- Partner with underwriting and verifications departments to ensure quality of loans

Kyle Knutson Page 3